Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Records on Microfilm 5976 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Fair Employment Practices Commission Files 1943 (Reel 23)
  - 0629. Fair Employment Practices Commission (1943). 303 pages., 3 (Reel 23)
    Major Topics: Notes relating to Fair Employment Practices Commission cases; National Mediation Board agreement between the Southeastern Carriers' Conference Committee and the Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen; mediation agreements between the Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen and the Illinois Central Railroad Company and the Gulf, Mobile, and Northern Railroad Company; summaries of discrimination complaints against railroad companies; executive order relating to discrimination by companies or agencies engaged in the fulfillment of war production contracts; Pittsburgh Plate Glass Company case; appointment of Monsignor Francis J. Haas as Fair Employment Practices Commission chairman; Milton Webster's address at the American Federation of Labor Post War Forum; operating relationship between the War Manpower Commission and Fair Employment Practices Commission; digest of Fair Employment Practices Commission railroad hearings; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies.
- Fair Employment Practices Commission Files 1944 (Reel 24)
  - 0001. Fair Employment Practices Commission (January-April 1944). 266 pages., 1 (Reel 24)
    Major Topics: Congressional bill to prohibit employment discrimination; Carter Carburetor Corporation case; Warner Electric Corporation case; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; report on status of Fair Employment Practices Commission discrimination cases docketed in Region IX; Malcolm Ross's address before the National Freedom Day Celebration; Inter-Race Peace Rally; Dow Chemical Company case; Northwest Mining and Exchange case; minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meetings; discrimination against Negroes by the railroad industry; report on experiences in Negro employment.
  - 0267. Fair Employment Practices Commission (May-July 1944). 231 pages., 2 (Reel 24)
    Major Topics: Complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; Fair Employment Practices Commission rules and regulations; minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meetings; summaries of Fair Employment Practices Commission cases in the Saint Louis area; National War Agencies Appropriation Bill; proposed executive order on discrimination against aliens; statements in support of Fair Employment Practices Commission; Malcolm Ross's address to the Baltimore branch of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored Peoples; congressional bill to prohibit employment discrimination; abolition of segregation in the armed forces.
  - 0498. Fair Employment Practices Commission (August-September 1944). 257 pages., 3 (Reel 24)
    Major Topics: Minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meetings; summaries of Fair Employment Practices Commission cases in Saint Louis area; McQuay-Norris Manufacturing Company case; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; Saint Louis Shipbuilding and Steel Company case; operational statistics for Fair Employment Practices Commission cases; agreement between Fair Employment Practices Commission and the Maritime Commission; Fair Employment Practices Commission jurisdiction; antidiscrimination clauses in defense contracts; congressional bill to prohibit employment discrimination.
  - 0755. Fair Employment Practices Commission (October-December 1944). 215 pages., 4 (Reel 24)
    Major Topics: Complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meetings; Fair Employment Practices Commission rules and regulations; discrimination by federal housing agencies; Fair Employment Practices Commission budget; summaries of Fair Employment Practices Commission cases; MCQuay-Norris Manufacturing Company case; Capital Transit Company case; Shell Oil Company case.
- Fair Employment Practices Commission Files 1944-1946 (Reel 25)
  - 0001. Fair Employment Practices Commission (1944). 201 pages., 1 (Reel 25)
    Major Topics: Report on the Negro in 1944; report on postwar labor stability; Marinship Corporation case; contract between the Los Angeles Railway Corporation and the Amalgamated Association of Street Electric Railway and Motor Coach Employees of America; congressional bill to prohibit employment discrimination; Fair Employment Practices Commission case load activity by month; operational statistics for Fair Employment Practices Commission cases; report on the Fair Employment Practices Commission and the employment of minority workers in transition to the postwar economy; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; Fair Employment Practices Commission rules and regulations; Fair Employment Practices Commission operations; report on nondiscrimination in war industries and the federal government.
  - 0202. Fair Employment Practices Commission (January-February 1945). 234 pages., 2 (Reel 25)
    Major Topics: Shell Oil Company case; summaries of reports from Fair Employment Practices Commission regional offices on status of transit cases; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; Fair Employment Practices Commission salaries and expenses; Fair Employment Practices Commission rules and regulations; McQuay-Norris Manufacturing Company case; Seafarers International Union case; report on major race riots in the United States; minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meeting.
  - 0436. Fair Employment Practices Commission (March-May 1945). 215 pages., 3 (Reel 25)
    Major Topics: Minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meetings; summaries of Fair Employment Practices Commission cases; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; Capital Transit Company case; proposal for a permanent Fair Employment Practices Commission; Shell Oil Company case; Seafarers International Union case.
  - 0651. Fair Employment Practices Commission (June-December 1945). 251 pages., 4 (Reel 25)
    Major Topics: Minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meetings; Fair Employment Practices Commission appropriations; status of Fair Employment Practices Commission cases; proposed Fair Employment Practices Commission reorganization; McDonnell Aircraft Corporation case; Capital Transit Company case; Fair Employment Practices Commission salaries and expenses; Olin Industries, Incorporated case; Texas and New Orleans Railroad Company case; agreement between the United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America, Congress of Industrial Organizations, and the Fair Employment Practices Commission; proposal for a permanent Fair Employment Practices Commission.
  - 0902. Fair Employment Practices Commission (January-June 1946). 55 pages., 5 (Reel 25)
    Major Topics: Displacement of wartime workers in Washington, District of Columbia; extension of the Fair Employment Practices Commission by Harry Truman; proposal for a permanent Fair Employment Practices Commission; outline for Fair Employment Practices Commission final report.
- Hearings 1948-1976 (Reel 26)
  - 0001. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Hearing for C.W. Allen, 1966. 15 pages., 1 (Reel 26)
    Major Topics: Charges filed against Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters members by the Dining Car Employees Local 351 under their union shop agreement with the Grand Trunk Western Railroad Company; memorandum of agreement between the Dining Car Employees' Union, Local 351 and the Grand Trunk Western Railroad Company.
  - 0016. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Hearing for S.P. Blake, 1966. 6 pages., 2 (Reel 26)
    Major Topic: Charges filed against Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters members by the Dining Car Employees Local 351 under their union shop agreement with the Grand Trunk Western Railroad Company.
  - 0022. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Hearing for A.R. Blanchette, 1968. 60 pages., 3 (Reel 26)
    Major Topics: Memorandum of agreement between the Canadian Railways and the associated railway unions representing their non-operating employees regarding job security; memorandum of agreement between the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters and the Canadian Pacific Railway Company.
  - 0082. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Hearing for N. Brawner, 1966. 8 pages., 4 (Reel 26)
  - 0090. [Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Hearing, Chicago, Burlington, and Quincy Railroad, April 1963]. 13 pages., 5 (Reel 26)
    Major Topic: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Chicago, Burlington and Quincy Railroad Company dispute before the National Railroad Adjustment Board regarding seniority rights.
  - 0103. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Hearing for the Fort Worth and Denver Railway Company, 1963. 70 pages., 6 (Reel 26)
    Major Topic: Dispute between the Brotherhood of Railway and Steamship Clerks and the Fort Worth and Denver Railway Company before the National Railroad Adjustment Board regarding termination of dining car service positions.
  - 0173. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Hearings: Kansas City Southern Railway Case, 1951. 55 pages., 7 (Reel 26)
    Major Topic: Dispute between the Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen and the Kansas City Southern Railway Company before the National Railroad Adjustment Board regarding use of train porters to perform brakemen's duties.
  - 0228. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Locomotive Firemen's Case, 1953. 204 pages., 8 (Reel 26)
    Major Topics: Discrimination against colored locomotive firemen; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters efforts to organize colored locomotive firemen; colored locomotive firemen's case against the Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen before the United States Supreme Court; proposed settlement of colored locomotive firemen's cases.
  - 0432. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Locomotive Firemen's Case, 1955. 36 pages., 9 (Reel 26)
    Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters efforts to organize colored locomotive firemen; colored locomotive firemen's case against the Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen in the United States District Court for the Northern District of Ohio.
  - 0468. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Hearing for Benjamin F. Morris. 1958. 175 pages., 10 (Reel 26)
    Major Topics: Benjamin F. Morris case against R.M. Willis and the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters in the circuit court of Jackson County, Missouri, and in the Missouri Supreme Court regarding discharge from Pullman Company for nonpayment of union dues.
  - 0643. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Hearing for Benjamin F. Morris, 1958. 224 pages., 11 (Reel 26)
    Major Topic: Benjamin F. Morris case against R.M. Willis and the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters in the Missouri Supreme Court regarding discharge from Pullman Company for nonpayment of union dues.
  - 0867. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Hearing for Benjamin F. Morris, 1958. 82 pages., 12 (Reel 26)
    Major Topics: Benjamin F. Morris case against R.M. Willis and the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters in the Missouri Supreme Court and in the circuit court of Jackson County, Missouri, regarding discharge from Pullman Company for nonpayment of union dues.
  - 0949. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Hearing for New Haven Case, 1948. 58 pages., 13 (Reel 26)
    Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters request for a National Mediation Board investigation into union representation dispute involving buffet and club car employees of the New York, New Haven, and Hartford Railroad Company employees; National Mediation Board proceedings and decision in the matter of the representation of employees of the New York, New Haven, and Hartford Railroad.
  - 1007. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Hearing for Eldrige Parker, 1970. 22 pages., 14 (Reel 26)
    Major Topic: Investigation of Eldridge Parker's job security claim against the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters.
  - 1029. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Hearing for Milton Philips, 1975. 16 pages., 15 (Reel 26)
    Major Topics: Statement by the American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations on seniority and layoffs; principles for seniority modification.
  - 1045. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Hearing for G.R. Tillman, 1966. 13 pages., 16 (Reel 26)
  - 1058. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Hearing for Union Shop Court Case, 1953. 17 pages., 17 (Reel 26)
    Major Topics: Complaint against the Seaboard Air Line Railroad Company restraining the carrier from enforcing its union shop agreement with the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters case against the Texas and Pacific Railway Company before the National Railroad Adjustment Board regarding abolition of position of train porter and reduction of employees occupying those positions to chair car porters.
  - 1075. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Hearing for J.W. Wesson, 1965. 7 pages., 18 (Reel 26)
    Major Topic: Investigation into alleged nonpayment of union dues by J.W. Wesson.
  - 1082. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Hearing for W. Wheeler, 1962. 119 pages., 19 (Reel 26)
    Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters complaint against the New York City system before the National Railroad Adjustment Board and the National Mediation Board regarding selling of pillows in day coaches by lounge car attendants.
  - 1201. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Hearing for J. L. Williams, G. Thomas, and John W. Amos. 1976. 14 pages., 20 (Reel 26)
    Major Topic: Complaint regarding seniority and working status of Amtrak sleeping car service attendants.
- Convention Correspondence 1948-1971 (Reel 27)
  - 0001. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - National Convention, Detroit, 1948 - General Papers. 45 pages., 1 (Reel 27)
    Major Topics: Convention publicity and arrangements; convention resolutions; list of convention delegates.
  - 0046. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - 7th Biennial Convention, 1950 - Resolutions. 106 pages., 2 (Reel 27)
    Major Topics: Convention resolutions; report of the Auditing Committee; constitutional amendment.
  - 0152. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - First Triennial Convention, 1953 - Program. 9 pages., 3 (Reel 27)
  - 0161. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - First Triennial Convention, 1953 - General Papers. 80 pages., 4 (Reel 27)
    Major Topics: Convention arrangements; convention delegates; convention program and publicity; convention receipts and expenses; post-convention meeting of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board.
  - 0241. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Second Triennial Convention, 1956 - General Papers. 23 pages., 1953; 5 (Reel 27)
    Major Topics: Convention arrangements; convention program and publicity.
  - 0264. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Third Triennial Convention, 1959 - General Papers. 122 pages., 6 (Reel 27)
    Major Topics: Convention arrangements; guest speakers for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters convention; convention expenses; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters labor education meeting; convention publicity; report of the Committee on Scientific Service and Safety Efficiency; list of discontinued Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters districts; financial and membership status of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters divisions; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters endorses National Association for the Advancement of Colored People program; railroad social insurance program.
  - 0386. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Third Triennial Convention, 1959 - General Papers. 115 pages., 7 (Reel 27)
    Major Topics: Report on Grievance and Claims Committee; list of officers of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters local divisions; convention outline; railroad carriers having agreements with the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; convention programs; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters labor education meeting; agreement between Southwest Reporters and the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; convention resolutions; list of convention delegates; G.E. Leighty's address to the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters convention.
  - 0501. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Third Triennial Convention, 1959 - Resolutions. 57 pages., 8 (Reel 27)
    Major Topics: Report of the Committee on Resolutions and Constitutions; convention resolutions; constitutional revisions.
  - 0558. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Third Triennial Convention, 1959 - Report of the Executive Committee. 23 pages., 9 (Reel 27)
  - 0581. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Third Triennial Convention, 1959 - Amendments to Constitution. 8 pages., 10 (Reel 27)
  - 0589. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Third Triennial Convention, 1959 - Resolutions. 141 pages., 11 (Reel 27)
    Major Topics: Convention resolutions; minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board pre-convention and post-convention meetings; report of the Train Chair Car Porters and Attendants Committee.
  - 0730. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Fourth Triennial Convention, 1962 - General Papers. 95 pages., 12 (Reel 27)
    Major Topics: Summary of matters handled by the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters on behalf of members employed by the Canadian Pacific Railroad Company; convention arrangements and publicity; second convention of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary; convention delegates; report of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board to the Fourth Triennial Convention; convention program.
  - 0825. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Fourth Triennial Convention, 1962 - General Papers. 144 pages., 13 (Reel 27)
    Major Topics: Report of the Finance Committee; convention agenda; report of the Train, Chair Car Porters and Attendants Committee; convention resolutions; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters constitutional amendments; A. Philip Randolph's address to the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Fourth Triennial Convention; convention program.
  - 0969. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Fifth Triennial Convention, 1965 - General Papers. 46 pages., 14 (Reel 27)
    Major Topics: Convention delegates; convention arrangements and program; memorial service for Milton Webster.
  - 1015. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Fiftieth Anniversary Convention, 1975 - Credentials. 37 pages., 15 (Reel 27)
    Major Topics: Statements by the American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations Executive Council on equal opportunity in housing, voter registration by mail, seniority and layoffs, and Title VII and the seniority system; efforts to merge Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters with larger union; need for expanding Equal Employment Opportunity Commission conciliation efforts under Title VII; report on union role in ending job discrimination; report on civil rights; list of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters local division officers.
  - 1052. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Fiftieth Anniversary Convention, 1975 - Congratulatory Letters and Telegrams. 115 pages., 16 (Reel 27)
- Membership Ledgers; General Files (American Train Dispatchers Association-Extra Porters) (Reel 28)
  - 0001. Box 62-1, no date. 51 pages., 1 (Reel 28)
    Major Topic: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters membership list.
  - 0052. Box 62-2. No date. 13 pages., 2 (Reel 28)
  - 0065. American Train Dispatchers Association (Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters). 11 pages., 1963; 3 (Reel 28)
    Major Topic: Cases pending before the Third Division of the National Railroad Adjustment Board
  - 0076. Annual $10 Tax Notice (To All Officers in Midwest Zone). 18 pages., 1952; 4 (Reel 28)
  - 0094. Application (17 Cooperating Railway Organizations). 6 pages., 1955; 5 (Reel 28)
    Major Topic: Effort by Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters to join the seventeen cooperating railway organizations that initiate wages, working conditions, and other movements in the interest of non-operating employees.
  - 0100. Army Discharge. 8 pages., 1942; 6 (Reel 28)
    Major Topic: Procedures to be followed for obtaining release or discharge of skilled workers age thirty-eight or over for the purpose of employment in essential industries.
  - 0108. Association of Western Railways. 62 pages., 1956; 7 (Reel 28)
    Major Topic: Colorado gross ton-mile truck tax.
  - 0170. Association of American Railroads. 2 pages., 1955; 8 (Reel 28)
    Major Topic: Association of American Railroads position on United States transportation policy.
  - 0172. Atlantic Coast Line Porters (CIO). 8 pages., 1949; 9 (Reel 28)
    Major Topic: Union representation dispute regarding employees of the Atlantic Coast Line Railroad.
  - 0180. Audit Report (Special Fund-Drexel National Bank). 15 pages., 1959; 10 (Reel 28)
    Major Topic: Statement of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters monthly receipts and disbursements of the special fund at the Drexel National Bank. August 31, 1959
  - 0195. Authorizations for Handling Board Cases. 4 pages., 1945; 11 (Reel 28)
    Major Topic: Authorization for handling of cases before the Fourth Division of the National Railroad Adjustment Board.
  - 0199. Away From Home Expenses - Chicago District Porters. 12 pages., 12 (Reel 28)
    No date.
  - 0211. Canadian Railway Board of Adjustment. 15 pages., 1921; 13 (Reel 28)
    Major Topic: Memorandum of agreement between the Canadian railways and members of railway unions; proposed sleeping car conductors bill.
  - 0226. Civil Rights Committee. 3 pages., 1964; 14 (Reel 28)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations housing and urban development program; meeting of American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations Civil Rights Committee.
  - 0229. Chicago-Midwest, Detroit-Pittsburgh Zone Conference. 203 pages., 1955; 15 (Reel 28)
    Major Topics: Report on the Chicago-Midwest and Detroit-Pittsburgh regional conference held at Chicago, Illinois; conference delegates; conference resolutions; conference arrangements; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters labor education meeting; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters leadership training conference in Montreal, Canada; conference program; speeches at conference by A. Philip Randolph and Horace Harper.
  - 0432. Conference Proceedings (of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Provisional Committee to Organize Colored) Locomotive Firemen, Jacksonville, Florida. 189 pages., 1947; 16 (Reel 28)
    December 2-3, 1947.
  - 0621. Colored Locomotive Firemen's Conference, Washington, District of Columbia. 21 pages., 1951; 17 (Reel 28)
    Major Topic: Report on the Tenth Annual Conference of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Provisional Committee for the Organization of Colored Locomotive Firemen.
  - 0642. Colored Locomotive Firemen's Conference. 10 pages., 1956; 18 (Reel 28)
    Major Topic: Notice of the Fifteenth Annual Conference of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Provisional Committee for the Organization of Colored Locomotive Firemen. May 25-26, 1956
  - 0652. Colored Locomotive Firemen's Conference. 4 pages., 1958; 19 (Reel 28)